A Guide to John Henry Ingram's Poe Collection
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Part One: Letters, Manuscripts, Other Documents
  - "IL CORVO," by GUIDO MENASCI, 1890.; [393]; TL. 6 pp. (Box 7)
    An eighteen-stanza translation of "The Raven" into Italian.
  - ULISSE ORTENSI, Rome, APCS in Italian to INGRAM, 1892.; [394] (Box 7)
    Ortensi requests that Ingram encourage favorable reception of his Italian prose version of Poe's poetry with the English editors to whom he has mailed copies.
  - WILLIAM HAND BROWNE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1893 June 22.; [395]; 2 pp. (Box 7)
    Newspapers are reprinting verses, obviously spurious, said to have been written by Poe on the flyleaf of a book he had borrowed from the University of Virginia. Browne encloses a copy of a letter from Henry C. Carey to John P. Kennedy, 8 December 1834, sending Kennedy "a small sum" in payment to his "friend" for "one of his tales" (i.e., "MS. Found in a Bottle"); Kennedy noted on 12 April 1851 that the sum was $20 forwarded to Poe from Eliza Leslie, editor of The Atlantic Souvenir (i.e., The Gift).
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1895 April 29.; [396]; 3 pp. (Box 7)
    Miss Poe encloses a photograph of a portrait of Poe that now belongs to her brother John Prentiss Poe, a photograph of a water-color portrait of Virginia Poe that is now hers, and an autograph taken from a letter from Poe to her father Judge Neilson Poe. Stone and Kimball Publishing Company has been allowed to use these things in their new edition of Poe's works; after they appear in those volumes they may be offered for sale. She thanks Ingram for his appreciation of her illustrious kinsman.
  - WILLIAM HAND BROWNE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1895 May 16.; [397]; 4 pp. (Box 7)
    That stuff about Poe and helium, if there be such a thing, is all newspaper silliness; because Poe wanted his balloon to go higher than any had gone before, he had to suppose a gas lighter than hydrogen. That Poe did anticipate some of the general conclusions of later science, Browne did try to show once in an article. Reverend John B. Tabb has recently written an epigram on Poe and his critics, especially George Woodberry, and the enclosed autographed copy is for Ingram's collection. Mentions Mark Twain. [Item 380 enclosed.]
  - E. C. STEDMAN, New York, ALS to INGRAM, 1895 September 5.; [398]; 4 pp. (Box 7)
    Stone and Kimball Publishing Company wishes to use Ingram's photographs of Poe and his mother in order that they might have all the pictures of Poe in one edition.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1895 October 26.; [399]; 3 pp. (Box 7)
    There is an engraved picture of Judge Neilson Poe and none of any kind of General David Poe, Sr. Stone and Kimball's fourth volume contains Miss Poe's photograph of Edgar; the ninth is to have that of Virginia. The poem "Alone" is in an album belonging to Mrs. Dawson, whose mother was a Mrs. Lucy Holmes Balderston, for whom Poe wrote the poem. A miniature and an old daguerreotype of Edgar are now owned in Baltimore, but they are not for sale.
  - JAMES S. COTTON, Kensington, England, ALS to INGRAM, 1897 February 22.; [400]; 3 pp. (Box 7)
    Cotton sees a "striking" similarity between the last stanza of George Darley's "The Wedding Wake" and two half-lines in Poe's "Lenore."
  - EDWARD V. VALENTINE, Richmond, ALS to INGRAM, 1897 June 2.; [401]; 1 p. (Box 7)
    The University of Virginia is to honor Poe on the fiftieth anniversary of his death, and Valentine has furnished the figure of $750 as the cost of a bust, for which Professor James A. Harrison is appealing for funds; his idea is to establish a memorial to Poe at the University, and the bust is to be placed in an alcove in the new library. [Item 907 is enclosed.]
  - ROBERT D'UNGER, M.D., Chicago, ALS to CHEVALIER ELMER ROBERT REYNOLDS, Washington, DC, 1897 October 29.; [402]; 10 pp. (Box 7)
    D'Unger gives an account of his association with Poe, which began in 1846, of Poe's heavy drinking, glumness, carping, and inability to make and keep friends. He thinks the story of Poe's having been "cooped" is "mere twaddle." Poe was a believer in "spirit friends," spiritualism not then being known. D'Unger was told that it was on a visit to "an improper house" that Poe met a girl named Lenore.
  - INGRAM'S REVIEW OF THE RAVEN. THE PIT AND THE PENDULUM, 1899.; [403]; MS. 1 p. (Box 7)
    In Ingram's judgment the combination of these two selections in the same volume published by Leonard Smithers and Company is curious and unexplained. He finds the book awkward, the illustrations childishly absurd, and the frontispiece a caricature; and he believes that whoever wrote "Some Account of the Author" has done nothing but retail libels gathered from the garbage of journalistic gossip.
  - J. M. CHEMFIELD [?], Lisbon, Portugal, ALS to INGRAM, 1901 April 20.; [404]; 4 pp. (Box 7)
    Chemfield lists Portuguese translations of Poe's works and the volumes he used in writing his Memoir of Poe.
  - "POE'S PURGATORY," by REV. JOHN B. TABB, 1904 May 21.; [405]; MS. 1 p. (Box 7)
    A three-stanza poem written for the Poe Alcove to be established at the University of Virginia.
  - "REJECTED," by REV. JOHN B. TABB, 1905 November 7.; [406]; MS. 1 p. (Box 7)
    One four-line stanza prompted by Poe's second rejection for admission to the Hall of Fame.
  - EDWARD V. VALENTINE, Richmond, ALS to INGRAM, 1906 September 12.; [407]; 2 pp. (Box 7)
    Does Ingram know of Robert or Robin Povall of St. Martin's-in-the-Field, about 1650? Virginians pronounced the name "Porsy." Samuel Pepys repeatedly mentions the name "Povey." Valentine encloses a clipping from the New York Herald, 9 September 1906, but the likeness in it of Sarah Elmira Royster Shelton is not good.
  - SIR EDMUND T. BEWLEY, Dublin, Ireland, ALS to INGRAM, 1906 November 13.; [408]; 3 pp. (Box 7)
    Bewley has criticized Sarah Helen Whitman's "romance" about Poe's ancestry in his book on the origin and early history of the Poe family and has given Ingram credit for the "surest testimony" on the subject gathered from Poe's family in Baltimore.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1908 October 20.; [409]; 3 pp. (Box 7)
    Miss Poe gives Ingram permission to use her photographs to illustrate his forthcoming articles on Poe. American magazines and newspapers are clamoring for Poe contributions for their January 1909 issues. Poe's The Raven and Other Poems can be bought for $30.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1908 November 10.; [410]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe encloses a photograph of Judge Neilson Poe that has not been reproduced in any American edition, a photograph of her brother the Honorable John Prentiss Poe, and one of William Clemm, Jr., Virginia Poe's father. Ingram may use these in his articles, but he is to return them to her later on.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1908 November 16.; [411]; 3 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe surveys her correspondence with Sir Edmund T. Bewley about Poe family ancestry.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1908 December 7.; [412]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    No picture of Rosalie Poe was ever made. She was a nervous, eccentric creature who idolized Edgar, and he was as considerate of her as was possible. American newspapers are full of articles about the forthcoming Poe centennial celebrations.
  - ULISSE ORTENSI, Aquila-Abruzzi, Italy, APCS in French to INGRAM, 1908 December 26.; [413] (Box 8)
    Ortensi declines to make a new impression of Poe's poems for the centennial, but he will do something worthy for the 19 January occasion.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1908 December 28.; [414]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe copies for Ingram from family records the birth and death dates of David Poe, Jr., Elizabeth Arnold Hopkins Poe, William Henry Leonard Poe, Edgar Allan Poe, and Rosalie Poe. She has a water-color portrait of Sam Poe, Edgar's uncle, who was a local wit and writer of clever verses. She knows of no portraits of David Poe or of David Poe, Jr., but she bought an oil painting of Edgar in a Baltimore shop in 1896. Professor James A. Harrison has a paper in the January Century Magazine entitled "Poe and Mrs. Whitman." Miss Poe has in her possession most of Sarah Helen Whitman's letters to Maria Clemm from 1859 on.
  - WILLIAM HAND BROWNE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 January 13.; [415]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Browne has forwarded an article from the Cosmopolitan magazine, the silliest thing about Poe that has yet appeared; the author is probably the wife of one of the younger generation of Poes. Browne has searched the October 1849 newspaper files for the name of the boat that probably brought Poe from Richmond to Baltimore, but without success. "Ryan's," where Joseph W. Walker reported finding Poe ill, was a public house called "Gunner's Hall" at 44 E. Lombard Street, which would be in the Fourth Ward. At that time the polls were usually held in the public houses, and the candidates saw that every voter had all the whiskey he wanted.
  - ULISSE ORTENSI, Aquila-Abruzzi, Italy, APCS in French to INGRAM, 1909 January 26.; [416] (Box 8)
    Ortensi has sent his new translation of Poe's life and poems and a copy of La Tribuna (Rome) for 20 January with his article on the Poe centennial. The publishers did not wait for the dedication of the new edition of the poems to Ingram, and the book was published without it.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 January 26.; [417]; 3 pp. (Box 8)
    The Poe centennial celebration was a great success in Baltimore. The University of Virginia has awarded Poe medals to Miss Poe and to Ingram.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 January 30.; [418]; 6 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe has no absolute proof that Edgar was born in Boston, but it is a family record and a family tradition. The Richmond Times-Dispatch, 17 January, has a photograph of the Reverend John Buchanan who baptized Edgar in December 1811. Poe's brother William Henry Leonard is said to have written beautiful verses in the album of a woman whom Ingram identifies as a Miss Durham. Edgar's uncle, Samuel Poe, was the son of General David Poe and Elizabeth Cairnes Poe. Miss Poe is "almost certain" that her old portrait of Edgar Poe was not taken from life; it has been copied by and for Professor James A. Harrison who plans to use it as he has used some of Sarah Helen Whitman's letters and many of Maria Clemm's letters to Neilson Poe. Ingram has Miss Poe's permission to use these as well as letters from Annie Richmond and Gabriel Harrison. She encloses a copy of the Latin inscription that was on the stone which Neilson Poe had prepared for Edgar's grave.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 February 11.; [419]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe has received permission from her nephew, Edwin W. Poe of Chicago, to have the water-color portrait of Sam Poe copied, at Ingram's expense, for his use.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 February 14.; [420]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe is posting to Ingram the photograph of Sam Poe; he may return by money order for $1.75 to cover cost. [The letter identifies Edwin Poe as residing in Baltimore, not Chicago: cf. Items 418 and 419.]
  - WILLIAM HAND BROWNE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 February 22.; [421]; 6 pp. (Box 8)
    Browne once wrote a now "forgotten paper of no account" for the New Eclectic magazine in which he plotted Poe's last trip from Richmond to Baltimore. He vouches for the validity of the note Joseph Walker wrote in October 1849 to Dr. Joseph E. Snodgrass asking him to come to Ryans' to help Edgar Poe; it was found in a bundle of letters from Poe to Dr. Snodgrass. Browne asks Ingram to write the life of Sir Francis Nicholson, soldier, statesman, and governor of Virginia and Maryland at the close of the seventeenth century. Browne has sent Ingram a report on James H. Whitty, a map of Baltimore showing Ryan's place, the place where Poe died, and the place he is buried. He encloses a poem by Reverend John B. Tabb entitled "In Touch."
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 February 27.; [422]; 6 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe encloses a copy she has made of Walter K. Watkins's newspaper article, "Where Poe was Born," the Boston Transcript, 13 January 1909, in which he discusses the plays in which David and Elizabeth Poe appeared from 1806 through 1809 and the songs they sang in them. He also attempts to fix the number of the house in which Poe was born.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 March 2.; [423]; 6 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe lists the nine letters from Poe to John P. Kennedy that are in the Peabody Institute as well as the letters and parts of autograph letters in her possession which were written by Poe.
  - JOHN H. INGRAM, London, TLS in French to LE DIRECTEUR DU MERCURE DE FRANCE, Paris, 1909 March 9.; [424]; 6 pp. (Box 8)
    Ingram asserts that M. Calvocoressi's article, " Edgar Poe, his biographers, his editors, his critics," which appeared in Le Mercure on 1 February 1909, contains numerous assertions which are inexact and prejudicial to himself and to the honor of Poe, for Calvocoressi says that there was no complete edition of Poe's works before the twentieth century and points to Professor James A. Harrison's seventeen-volume edition, published by T. Y. Crowell in 1902, as proof. Ingram's own edition of 1874, published by Adam and Charles Black, Edinburg, and the Stedman-Woodberry edition, published by Stone and Kimball, Chicago, 1895, are better, Ingram insists, because on the whole Professor Harrison's edition is bad.
  - ARTHUR CONAN DOYLE, Sussex, England, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 March 10.; [425]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Conan Doyle appreciates Ingram's letter and his present of a book about Poe, which he shall always prize. He alludes to a dinner honoring Poe centennial which is reported in Items 990 and 991.
  - ALFRED VALLETTE, Paris, ALS in French to INGRAM, 1909 March 11.; [426]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Vallette will publish Ingram's letter correcting M. Calvocoressi's article in Le Mercure de France on 1 April.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 March 22.; [427]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe justifies the charge of $1.75 for the photograph of Sam Poe. She gives Ingram permission to use all of the letters she has sent him in his new biography of Poe.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 March 24.; [428]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe sends Ingram copies of the nine letters from Poe to John P. Kennedy that are in the Peabody Institute as well as a copy of Sarah Helen Whitman's letter to Mrs. Clemm of 28 October 1849. [Item 67 enclosed.]
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 March 26.; [429]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe sends Ingram a copy of Poe's letter to Maria Clemm, 18 September 1848.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 April 1.; [430]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe asks Ingram when his new biography of Poe will be forthcoming.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 April 16.; [431]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe has received Ingram's money order [for $1.75 to cover the cost of photographing the water-color of Sam Poe ]. Her brother, John Prentiss Poe, was present at the second burial of Virginia Poe and believes he has an account of it in his library at home. William F. Gill died several years ago. [Gill was not to die until 1917.]
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 May 18.; [432]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe encloses an account of the reinterment of Virginia Poe from the Baltimore Sun, 20 January 1885. [Item 846 enclosed.]
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 June 22.; [433]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe regrets Ingram's continued indisposition. She has given her nephew, Reverend Neilson Poe Carey, a letter of introduction to Ingram.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 October 11.; [434]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Eugene L. Didier, author of The Poe Cult, has for years been "giving out articles," most of them of no literary or other value, and readers quite understand his status.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 November 9.; [435]; 3 pp. (Box 8)
    John Prentiss Poe is dead, and Miss Poe encloses a copy of the Memorial Meeting of the Bench and Bar of Baltimore City held in his honor. She gives Ingram permission to use the valentine poem by Virginia Poe in any way he chooses and regrets that she has no other verses by her.
  - WILLIAM HAND BROWNE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 end of November-December 9.; [436]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Browne encloses a copy of an undated letter from Maria Clemm to an unidentified addressee requesting money for herself and her children. Browne obtained this letter from the addressee's grandson who very positively refuses to allow his grandfather's name to be mentioned.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 December 14.; [437]; 3 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe encloses Professor Killis Campbell's articles on Poe from the Nation, 11 March and 1 June 1909. She thinks that Ingram should put on dynamo speed and finish his new biography of Poe, or in the face of new competition, he may be made to blush at his want of knowledge and lack of materials. Neilson Poe was born in Baltimore on 11 August 1809 and died there on 3 January 1884; his wife, Josephine Emily Clemm Poe, died in Baltimore on 13 January 1889; both are buried in Greenmount Cemetery, Baltimore.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1909 December 24.; [438]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Professor Killis Campbell has sent Miss Poe copies of his articles on Poe printed in the Nation, and she forwards them to Ingram.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1910 January 4.; [439]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe encloses another installment of Professor Killis Campbell's articles on Poe from the Nation.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1910 February 1.; [440]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe encloses a copy of what is possibly the last of Professor Killis Campbell's articles on Poe in the Nation. She has deliberately refrained from writing to Campbell, but he is coming to call on her in Baltimore.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1910 March 30.; [441]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    There is an uncut edition of Poe's poems advertised for sale in the Armstrong Library sale to be held in Boston in April.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1910 July 12.; [442]; 4 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe furnishes dates from the Poe family records: children of William Clemm, Jr., and Maria Poe Clemm -- Henry Clemm, born 10 September 1818, died young and unmarried; Maria Clemm, born 22 August 1820, died 5 November 1822; Virginia Elizabeth Clemm, born 13 August 1822, baptized by Bishop James Kemp on 5 November 1822, married to Edgar Poe by the Reverend Mr. Converse, Richmond, 16 May 1836, died at Fordham on 30 January 1847. It is said that J. P. Morgan and Dodd, Mead and Company have the most valuable collections of Poeana. Now that Ingram has finished writing his biography of Thomas Chatterton, he should give his Raven the right of way and push it to a finish and have the "last word" before he is eclipsed by a score of presumptuous amateurs.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1910 November 15.; [443]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe is pleased that Ingram is hard at work on his biography of Poe. The commendations of his biography of Thomas Chatterton are interesting.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1911 January 3.; [444]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe asks Ingram for a list of old American papers and magazines that he needs for reference.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1911 February 6.; [445]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Eugene Didier apparently thinks his The Poe Cult, and Other Poe Papers is the only worthwhile "edition" of Poe.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1911 February 28.; [446]; 3 pp. (Box 8)
    William Henry Leonard Poe wrote some verses in an album belonging to Rosa Durham, to whom he was supposed to have been engaged; but the album was destroyed by fire. Miss Poe copies for Ingram an account of the death of General David Poe, from the Baltimore American, Saturday, 19 October 1816.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1911 July 7.; [447]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    Professor Killis Campbell has visited Miss Poe and has promised to share his Poe materials with her, which she will send to Ingram.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1911 July 18.; [448]; 1 p. (Box 8)
    She sends Ingram a clipping, and notes that "Dr. Charles W. Kent will doubtless give you 1500 authorities to verify his declaration." The unidentified newsclipping pasted on this letter states that Dr. Kent, Professor of English at the University of Virginia, declared at Morgantown, WV, 14 July 1911, that Edgar Poe "was not killed by excessive drinking but was the victim of a thief" who drugged him in order to rob him of a purse containing $1,500.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1911 September 5.; [449]; 3 pp. (Box 8)
    The completion of the Poe monument to be erected in Baltimore is assured by adding a gift of $5,000 from Orrin C. Painter to the sum already in hand. Sir Moses Ezekiel has signed the contract, and the monument is to be finished in two years. Miss Poe has given Professor Killis Campbell a list of Ingram's "wants," and he has promised to write to Ingram.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1911 September 9.; [450]; 3 pp. (Box 8)
    Professor Killis Campbell writes to Miss Poe that his Poe gleanings this summer were disappointingly small.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1912 January 5.; [451]; 4 pp. (Box 8)
    Orrin C. Painter has had a $500 wrought-iron gate put in the wall of Westminster Churchyard, giving a fine view of Poe's grave from the street. Miss Poe's nephew Edgar has been elected by a large vote to the office of Attorney General of Maryland, the same office his father, John Prentiss Poe, held for twenty years.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1912 March 15.; [452]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    On 19 January 1912, the Poe monument in Westminster churchyard was decorated with laurel wreaths and superb white roses.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1912 March 27.; [453]; 6 pp. (Box 8)
    Poe's impassioned letter from Richmond to Maria Clemm in Baltimore, which Neilson Poe refused to allow anyone to publish because it was so personal, was dated 29 August 1835. None of the Poe family knows anything of William Henry Leonard Poe's visits to Greece and Russia. Miss Poe encloses a copy of some "puerile verses" by W. H. L. Poe which Ingram may use as he sees fit. She quotes from Mrs. Clemm's letter to Neilson Poe, 27 September 1870: "You have been a dear kind son to me. I wish you, when God calls me, to see to my burial." Mrs. Clemm's last note to Neilson Poe was dated 9 January 1871; she died the following month.
  - LEWIS NATHANIEL CHASE, London, ALS to INGRAM, 1912 April 11.; [454]; 2 pp. (Box 8)
    Chase requests permission to quote from Ingram's "magnum opus" in his "Poe" contribution to the "Poetry and Life" series. Chase encloses an article on Coleridge to indicate the nature of his own task in writing about Poe.
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1912 May 2.; [455]; 5 pp. (Box 8)
    Miss Poe has no idea why William Henry Leonard Poe was named Leonard. Miss Dawson has allowed her to copy from her album Poe's poem "Alone," which he wrote in it, and his brother's poem "I Have Gazed on Woman's Cheek," which Poe copied into it. If Ingram wishes, she will copy for his use all of the last letters Poe wrote to Sarah Helen Whitman [Published in James A. Harrison's 1909 volume on the subject].
  - AMELIA F. POE, Baltimore, ALS to INGRAM, 1912 May 10.; [456]; 4 pp. (Box 8)